{
  "quizInfo": {
    "Subject": "Data and Digital Communications",
    "Term": "Prelims",
    "Title": "Quiz Reviewer for Prelims",
    "LastModified": "20 September 2024",
    "Authors": [
      "Alexander Oro"
    ],
    "References": [
      "01_Handout_1 & 01_Handout_1"
    ]
  },
  "quizData": [
    {
      "question": "In network coverage, this network interconnects LANs in a campus or city area",
      "answer": "Metropolitan Area Network",
      "choices": [
        "Metropolitan Area Network",
        "Personal Area Network",
        "Local Network Area",
        "Wide Area Network"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "This is the process of converting data into radio waves by adding information to an electronic or optical carrier signal",
      "answer": "Modulation",
      "choices": [
        "Modulation",
        "Noise",
        "Amplitude",
        "Sampling"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is the trasnmission of electric current projected into space in the form of waves",
      "answer": "Radio",
      "choices": [
        "Radio",
        "Telegraph",
        "Smoke Signals",
        "Telephone"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this topology, all nodes are interconnected by a single link with one node; the master node and the other nodes are secondary or slave nodes.",
      "answer": "Multidrop",
      "choices": [
        "Multidrop",
        "Point-to-Point",
        "Point-to-Multipoint",
        "Ring"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is the modulation technique in which the carrier amplitude varies based on analog baseband information signal to be transmitted in a wireless medium.",
      "answer": "Amplitude Modulation",
      "choices": [
        "Amplitude Modulation",
        "Frequency Modulation",
        "Phase Modulation",
        "Sampling"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In this topology, one node is connected to multiple nodes, each in a point-to-point manner.",
      "answer": "Point-to-Multipoint",
      "choices": [
        "Point-to-Multipoint",
        "Multidrop",
        "Point-to-Point",
        "Bus"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "This process essentially converts analog amplitudes to discrete levels",
      "answer": "Sampling",
      "choices": [
        "Sampling",
        "Encoding",
        "Attentuation",
        "Distortion"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is the modulation technique in which the carrier phase varies based on analog baseband information signal to be transmitted in a wireless medium",
      "answer": "Phase Modulation",
      "choices": [
        "Phase Modulation",
        "Amplitude Modulation",
        "Frequency Modulation",
        "Attentuation"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is like the multidrop topology except that there is no master-slave relationship in which all nodes are peers",
      "answer": "Bus",
      "choices": [
        "Bus",
        "Star",
        "Ring",
        "Point-to-Multipoint"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It revolutionized long-distance communication by sending electric signals in Morse code in between two stations.",
      "answer": "Telegraph",
      "choices": [
        "Telegraph",
        "Radio",
        "Smoke Signals",
        "Telephone"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "This type of noise caused by natural phenomena such as lightning discharge in thunderstorms and other electrical disturbances that occur in nature",
      "answer": "Atmospheric",
      "choices": [
        "Atmospheric",
        "Man-made",
        "Extraterrestrial noise",
        "Thermal"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In data communication, this device performs to recover the message signal",
      "answer": "Receiver",
      "choices": [
        "Receiver",
        "Transmitter",
        "Source",
        "Source Encoder"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is the modulation technique in which the carrier frequency varies based on analog baseband information signal to be transmitted in a wireless medium",
      "answer": "Frequency Modulation",
      "choices": [
        "Frequency Modulation",
        "Amplitude Modulation",
        "Phase Modulation",
        "Sampling"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "In data communication, this device converts the information into an electrical form called message signal",
      "answer": "Source Encoder",
      "choices": [
        "Source Encoder",
        "Receiver",
        "Transmitter",
        "Source"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "It is an instrument designed for the simultaneous transmission oof human voice",
      "answer": "Telephone",
      "choices": [
        "Telephone",
        "Telegraph",
        "Radio",
        "Smoke Signals"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which signal form changes without exhibiting a pattern or cycle that repeats over time?",
      "answer": "Nonperiodic",
      "choices": [
        "Nonperiodic",
        "Periodic",
        "Analog",
        "Digital"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which refers to the number of waves that pass a given point in each period?",
      "answer": "Frequency",
      "choices": [
        "Frequency",
        "Amplitude",
        "Noise",
        "Wavelength"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is directly related to the frequency of a given waveform?",
      "answer": "Wavelength",
      "choices": [
        "Wavelength",
        "Frequency",
        "Amplitude",
        "Noise"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the process of converting digital data into digital signals?",
      "answer": "Line Coding",
      "choices": [
        "Line Coding",
        "Sampling",
        "Encoding",
        "Transmitting"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which converts discrete signals into highs (1) and lows (0), making these the binary equivalent of a time-bound discrete signal?",
      "answer": "Encoding",
      "choices": [
        "Encoding",
        "Line Coding",
        "Sampling",
        "Transmitting"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is the modulation technique in which carrier amplitude varies based on analog baseband information signal to be transmitted in a wireless medium?",
      "answer": "AM",
      "choices": [
        "AM",
        "FM",
        "PM",
        "DM"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which is defined as an unwanted signal that is superimposed on a desired signal?",
      "answer": "Noise",
      "choices": [
        "Noise",
        "Attenuation",
        "Distortion",
        "Frequency"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which type of noise arises from the time-dependent fluctuations in electrical current?",
      "answer": "Shot",
      "choices": [
        "Shot",
        "Thermal",
        "Extraterrestrial",
        "Atmospheric"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    },
    {
      "question": "Which signal is represented as a sine wave?",
      "answer": "Analog",
      "choices": [
        "Analog",
        "Digital",
        "Periodic",
        "Nonperiodic"
      ],
      "reference": "Quiz_Reviewer",
      "term": "Prelims"
    }
  ]
}